(773) 800-ZEVG • Evanston, IL 60203 zevgoldberg [at] gmail.com responsive HTML version at resume.zevgoldberg.com

Zev Goldberg

Senior Software Engineer



Summary

Thoughtful, thorough and inclusive. With more than 25 years of experience, I am looking to be a good citizen on the internet, building the next generation of web applications. I seek understanding of end-users, stakeholders, UX and Product teams to gather consensus to build interfaces that are perceivable, operable, understandable and robust. Noisemaker and Noisemaker-maker. Guitar FX Mad Scientist.

Specialties

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, component frameworks, REST API, Single Page Applications, React.js, Next.js, Svelte, Node.js, Jest, Storybook, Chromatic, Universal Design, UX/UI, accessibility, responsive layout, guitar FX

Experience

GRAINGER

CHICAGO, IL | APR 2015-SEP 2024 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

- $_\ \ HTML, CSS, Javascript, j Query, Node. js, Svelte, React, Type Script, Story Book, Jest$
- Develop components and pages for e-commerce application for Fortune 500 company as part of a team
- Convert legacy pages to faster and more robust Single Page Applications
- _ Participate in regular on-call rotation for troubleshooting issues with released code
- _ Write documentation for components in Storybook for other developer teams
- Define accessibility requirements and shape approach for implementation of UI components
- Implement mechanism for onsite employees to provide feedback on internal search results
- _ Automate processes with GitHub Actions and Workflows, Bash scripts

SEARS IR LABS

CHICAGO, IL | MAY 2014-MAR 2015 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Bootstrap, Less, Angular-UI, Grunt, Underscore, Github
- Develop gamified learning management application
- Convert UX documents and mock-up images into functioning sections of the application
- _ Troubleshoot layout and functionality issue

MINT CHIP

SKOKIE, IL | MARCH 2014-MAY 2014 | SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

- _ HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Wordpress, Git, Beanstalk
- Develop responsive Wordpress sites for SMB clients

CRITICAL MASS

CHICAGO, IL | DECEMBER 2013-FEBRUARY 2014 | SENIOR DEVELOPER

- $_$ Web Performance Tools, Google PageSpeed Tools, YSlow, ImageOptim
- Develop strategies and plans to measure and improve load times and perceived performance of existing websites

CHICAGO TRIBUNE

CHICAGO, IL | APRIL 2012-NOVEMBER 2013 | SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

- HTML5, Advanced CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, responsive layout, touch-enabled, cross-browser, device-agnostic, SVN, Photoshop, InDesign
- Develop major metropolitan online newspaper as a device-agnostic JavaScript application
- Convert requirements documents and mock-up images into functioning sections of the website
- Troubleshoot layout and functionality issues
- _ Interview and on-board Front-End engineer candidates

JSPACE.COM, LLC

CHICAGO, IL | NOVEMBER 2010-APRIL 2012 | WEB DEVELOPER

- HTML5, Advanced CSS, Smarty, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Modernizr, HTML5
 Boilerplate, NetBeans, Subversion (command-line and TortoiseSVN), Photoshop,
 Fireworks, PHP, Zend Framework, MySQL (command-line and phpMyAdmin)
- Lead development of HTML and CSS for a large social network, news, venue/city guide and dating site
- Convert requirements documents and mock-up images into functioning sections of the website
- Design and develop templates and a template structure
- Choose and implement the latest HTML5/CSS3 and modern JavaScript solutions for simpler code creation and greatest cross-browser compatibility

CHICAGO SUN-TIMES

CHICAGO, IL | OCTOBER 2010-NOVEMBER 2010 | FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

- _ X/HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop
- Migrate several classified ads systems into the new one, maintaining the latest look-and-feel styles

MYWRIGLEYVILLE.COM

CHICAGO, IL | MAY 2010-AUGUST 2010 | WEB DEVELOPER

- LAMP, Joomla, OOP, X/HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, ColdFusion, Photoshop,
 Illustrator, social media, Android
- Help develop and maintain company's extensive web presence
- _ Develop and maintain partner websites

EXTENDED CARE CONSULTING

EVANSTON, IL | MAY 2006-APRIL 2010 | SENIOR DATABASE AND APPLICATION DEVELOPER

- LAMP, Joomla, OOP, X/HTML, CSS, JavaScript (Prototype, Scriptaculous, etc.), Ajax,
 Excel, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, SubVersion, Fiery Print Server
- Design, develop, code and test online database applications with multiple access levels, user management, custom user interface, reporting and graphs used by more than 300 people spanning several departments
- Provide technical support for aforementioned applications and anything computer related
- Design, develop and maintain more than thirty websites for all Extended Care nursing facilities using a customized Content Management System that I set up
- Provide complete graphics services for promotional materials including layout,
 copy-editing, printing and liaison to professional printing services
- Design, layout, copy-edit and distribute (2,000 copies) for bi-weekly corporate newsletter
- Consultant and extra hand to IT department, specializing in scripting, Linux,
 Windows and security

Education

COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO

Chicago, IL | 1994–1998 | Computer Animation and Film

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO

Chicago, IL | 1993–1994 | Computer Science